[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Let's start by discussing some areas in which recommender systems are playing
现在我们讨论一些推荐系统
a really active role behind the scenes.
起到重要作用场景的 领域时候
And as we're gonna see in this discussion, depending on the specific application
我们将会看到我们想要优化的特定应用的
different aspects of the objective we're trying to optimize are gonna be important.
不同优化目标会变得很重要
But before we start talking about recommenders systems,
在我们讨论推荐系统之前
it's really important to talk about the idea of personalization,
我们有必要先谈一谈个性化思想
because personalization is transforming our experience of the world.
因为个性化需要结合我们自身的经验
As we talked about in the clustering and similarity module, there are lots and
当我们谈到聚类和相似度部分时
lots of articles out there.
我们可以参考很多文章
In lots and lots of webpages.
和很多很多的网页
And we can't possibly be expected to browse all of them.
当然我们可能没法全部看完
So another example here is YouTube.
另外一种资源是YouTube视频
So YouTube,
YouTube网站上
it's quoted that there are roughly 100 hours of video recorded per minute.
每分钟就有大约100小时的视频
And the question is what do I care about.
其实我最关心的是
You know, I go on YouTube and I wanna watch some video that's of interest to me.
哪些YouTobe上的视频是让我感兴趣的
So this is an example, clearly, of information overload.
这是一个很好的信息过载的例子
There's just way too much content there for me possibly to be able to go and for
网站上有太多我可以看的内容
me to find what I'm interested in without somebody helping that content come to me.
很难在没有人帮助的情况下找到我感兴趣的东西
So browsing, the traditional form of browsing, is history.
所以传统的浏览模式成为了历史
There needs to be some way in which
我们需要更好的方法
the content that's relevant to me is automatically discovered.
可以自动发现适合我的内容
And so this the notion of personalization, where we wanna connect users like myself,
这就是个性化的概念
who goes to YouTube and items which, in this case,
在这个例子里我们想要将YouTobe用户
are gonna be videos on YouTube need to somehow be connected.
和YouTobe上的视频关联起来
Okay, so,
好了
personalization is gonna play a key role in this notion of recommender systems and
个性化在推荐系统中扮演着重要的角色
now let's talk about some examples where recommender systems are very important.
我们再举一些例子说明推荐系统的重要性
So one very classic example that we mentioned a little bit earlier was this
一个之前提到的非常经典的例子是
idea of Netflix where, here people go and they watch videos.
在线观看视频的平台Netflix
And Netflix has this goal of trying to make suggestions of which movies or
Netflix的目标是推荐给用户一些
TV shows might be of interest the person who's come to this site.
他们可能感兴趣的电影或电视节目
And the question is, how are we gonna go about doing these recommendations.
问题是我们怎样去做出这样的推荐
Another example, again going back to something we talked about earlier,
另一个我们之前谈过的例子是
is Amazon making product recommendations.
Amazon的产品推荐
So you go on to Amazon, you purchase some product, and you'll see on the site that
如果你去Amazon买东西
it makes a recommendation of other products you might be interested in.
它会推荐一些你可能感兴趣的其他商品
But one important thing to incorporate in these recommendations
值得注意的是推荐过程中
is the fact that not only do you have to take into account
不仅仅需要考虑到
the interest that the person had in this one session.
此次购物过程用户所感兴趣的商品
So for example here we're showing that somebody bought a book about websites and
举例来说 如果某人买了一本网站方面的书
might be interested in another book about web applications or for
他可能对其他网络应用程序的书感兴趣
example my most recent purchase on Amazon were shoes for my son but
或者  我最近买了一双鞋给我儿子
the interest that I have in making that purchase of shoes isn't my only interest.
但是这些产品不是我个人的兴趣
I'm not only looking for shoes for a one-year old.
我并不只是需要一岁小孩的鞋子
There are lots of other reasons why I go to Amazon and make purchases.
我还有很多其他商品会在Amazon上买
And if you look at my history of purchases you're gonna be able to make much
如果你查看我的购物记录
better recommendations for me than just based on a single session.
你会做出比仅凭一次购物记录更好的推荐
And likewise, recommendations might change over time.
同样地 推荐商品会逐渐的变化
So there's interest in making recommendations, for example,
做推荐是一件很有意思的事情
what I might be interested in purchasing today.
如果你想知道我今天可能会买什么
So if you look at my purchase history a year ago,
如果你查看我去年的购物记录
I was buying a lot of newborn products.
会发现我买了很多的新生产品
So newborn baby products.
额  新生儿产品
But that's probably not something that I'm very likely to purchase today.
但是我很可能不会再买那些商品了
So the recommendations that Amazon presents to me today
所以Amazon推荐的产品
have to adapt with time.
应该随着时间变化
So just as on demand video with personalized recommendation has really
其实个性化推荐的视频已经
revolutionized how people watch movies and TV shows, likewise there are a lot
改变了人们看电影和电视节目的方式
of websites that provide streaming audio with personal recommendations.
同时出现了很多结合个性化推荐的流媒体网站
However, in this case unlike thinking about on demand video
接下来 不考虑需推荐的视频
here we want one song to play after another.
我们考虑一首接一首的歌曲
And what we want is we want some coherent stream of songs.
我们想要的是一些连续播放的歌曲
So songs I've liked I wanna play similar songs.
一些曲风相似的歌曲
I don't wanna rapidly switch between for example some cafe Indi songs,
我不想从Indi温和的咖啡厅歌曲
all of a sudden playing a heavy metal song.
突然变成狂热的重音乐歌曲
But at the same time
与此同时
I don't want a song I just heard to play again and again and again.
我也不想一首歌无限单曲循环
So I want some sense of recommendations that are coherent but
所以我想要一种连贯的歌曲推荐
I also want them to provide a diverse sequence of songs for me to listen to.
另一方面 我希望这些歌曲有一定的多样性
Okay, well another critical area where recommender systems have
好的 推荐系统活跃的另一个领域是
played a very active role is in social networking.
社交网络
So for example on Facebook there are tons and tons of users.
举例来说  Facebook拥有非常大量的用户
And we wanna form connections between these users.
我们想明确用户间的关联关系
So for example here might be a graph of connections between users on Facebook and
假设我们有一个Facebook用户关系图
maybe I'm this pink node right here, and
我是这个粉红色的节点
Facebook wants to recommend other people I might be interested in connecting with.
Facebook想推荐一些我可能感兴趣的人
In this application and it's important to note that both the users and
在这个应用场景中 值得注意的是
the quote unquote items are of the same type.
用户和推荐、被推荐的产品两者的类型是一样的
We're both people.
他们都是人
So when I'm a user on Facebook the things that are being recommended to me,
当我在使用Facebook时 它推荐给我的
the items, they are other people.
是其他的人
So we're gonna end up with users and
最后 本次课程我们将以
items being exactly the same type in this application.
用户和物品类型一样的实例结尾
But the recommendation system that we've talked about have really focused on
之前我们谈到的推荐系统应用领域
online media.
集中在网络媒体
But more and more, people are realizing other area's in which recomender systems
其实人们逐渐意识到在其他的领域
can play a really important role.
可以发挥重要的作用
And just as one example,
举例来说
we can think about what is call drug-target interactions.
回想一下药物靶相互作用（drug-target interactions）
And here, maybe we have some drug that's been studied, for example,
假设我们现在有一些已经被研究的药物
let's talk about aspirin.
比如说阿司匹林（aspirin）
It's been well studied as a treatment for headaches.
它被研究用作头痛的治疗药
But what if it's discovered to have some other possible use?
但是如果发现它还有其他的用途呢
So for example, for blood thinning, for heart patients?
比如说作为血液稀释剂或者心脏病药
If we can find these types of relationships,
如果我们发现了这些作用
if we can repurpose this drug for some other treatment,
我们可以增加这种药物的这些用途
then that could be really useful, because it's really quite costly and
这样会带来很多便利
lengthy process to get FDA approval for a completely new drug, but
因为得到美国食品药物管理局（FDA）对 新药的批准是一个代价很高且耗时的过程
if we can take a drug where the types of side effects and
服用一种副作用和潜在风险都已被
the possible risks associated are already well known and well studied.
很好研究的药物是一件比较放心的事情
Then it's a lot easier to get approval for treatment with some other condition,
批准已有药物的其他作用 是一件相对来说很简单的事情
so this is a case where we might say, if you like Aspirin for headaches,
因此如果你选择阿司匹林治头痛
you might also like Aspirin for your heart condition.
你也会用它作心脏病药
So recommender systems are playing an active role in medicine as just an example
所以推荐系统在医疗领域有不错的应用
of the diversity of applications where we see these types of systems.
而且我们可以看到它在 如之前所讲的很多领域都大展身手
>> [MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: dalongraymond | 审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translate Community